伦敦 2012
失踪 你见过她吗 简·麦克吉伦
梅芙 你还好吗
Maeve? You OK?
不 亲爱的 我不好
No, love. I'm not.
需要我帮你叫医生吗
You want me to call a doctor?
医生可帮不上忙
Doctor can't help.
你 你感觉不到吗 翠西
Can't...can't you feel it, Trish?
我什么也没感觉到
I can't feel anything.
孩子们 快进屋
Boys... get indoors!
快进去 快让他们进去
Get inside! Get 'em inside!
你怎么了 他们可没做什么坏事
What's up with you? They ain't doing nothing wrong.
又来了
It's happening again!
在老桉树上
In the old gum tree
他是树丛的欢乐欢乐国王
Merry, merry king of the bush is he
笑呀 笑翠鸟笑呀
Laugh, kookaburra Laugh,
笑翠鸟你的生活一定好愉快
kookaburra Gay your life must be.
他们不安全  - 他们在院子里
They're not safe! - They're in the garden!
它就喜欢这样
That's what it likes!
它就喜欢趁玩耍的时候
It likes it when they're playing!
快让他们进屋里 求求你了
Get 'em in! I'm begging you!
他是树丛的欢乐欢乐国王
Merry, merry king of the bush is he
笑呀 笑翠鸟笑呀
Laugh, kookaburra Laugh,
笑翠鸟你的生活一定好愉快
kookaburra Gay your life must be.
好吧 我会好好看着他们的 走吧
Right, I've got my beady eyes on 'em. Come on, come on.
不要  - 汤姆
No! - Tom?
你是谁  - 他去哪了
What are you? - Where's he gone?
你想要我们的孩子干什么
What do you want with our children?
神秘博士 第二季第十一集
畏惧她
肖恩·沃德
最热单曲 快下载吧
所以这次是不远的未来
So, near future, yeah?
我不过一时心血来潮 但这次就卡在了这里
I had a passing fancy. Only it didn't pass. It stopped.
第三十届奥林匹克运动会
Thirtieth Olympiad.
不可能 我怎么没想到 太棒了
No way! Why didn't I think of this? That's great.
那些希腊裸男就好像昨天才见过
Only seems like yesterday a few naked Greek blokes.
到处扔着铁饼
were tossing a discus about,
在沙地上玩摔跤
wrestling with each other in the sand
周围的人群低吼着
as the crowds stood around baying...
不 等等 那是地中海俱乐部
No, wait a minute, that was Club Med.
正好赶上今晚的开幕式
Just in time for the opening ceremony tonight.
觉着你会喜欢 上次伦敦奥运可是轰动一时
I thought you'd like that. Last one they had in London was dynamite.
温布利 1948
Wembley, 1948.
我喜欢得不得了 又回去重新看了一次
I loved it so much that I went back and watched it all over again.
拿火炬的小伙伴
Fella carrying the torch.
非常可爱 他叫干什么来着
Lovely chap. What was his...?
约翰·马克吧
John, Mark?
腿像洗烟斗的 却像灵犬一样强壮
Legs like pipe-cleaners but strong as a whippet...
博士
Doctor.
那个年代 所有人都会去茶会  - 博士
In those days, everyone had a tea-party to go to. - Doctor!
你吃过上面撒了脆滚珠的蛋糕吗
You ever have cakes with crunchy ball-bearings on top?
博士你应该看看这个  - 要知道
Doctor! You should see this! - You know... ?
整个银河系就找不出
Nobody else in this entire galaxy
第二个做可食用滚珠的星球 天才
has ever bothered to make edible ball-bearings. Genius!
你觉得是谁拐走了他们
What's taking them do you think?
失踪人口
把孩子们从这样一条普通的街上劫走
Snatching children from a thoroughly ordinary street like this.
为什么这里这么冷
And why's it so cold?
有什么东西给这里降温
Something's reducing the temperature.
失踪 你见过他吗 戴尔·希克斯 失踪日期 2012年7月27日
上面说都是这周失踪的
Says they all went missing this week.
为什么有人要这么做
Why would a person do something like this?
为什么你觉得是人
What makes you think it's a person?
无论是什么 都让这条街的人吓到死
Whatever it is, it's got the whole street scared to death.
博士 你
Doctor, what...?
又来了 今天第五起 这不寻常 是吧
There you go! Fifth today! That's not natural, is it?
不知道怎么回事 离上次保养还不到一个月
Don't know what happened. I had it serviced less than a month ago.
别解释了 兄弟
Don't even try and explain it, mate.
所有车都这样 简直疯了
All the cars are doing it and you know what, it's bonkers.
疯了
Bonkers.
来吧 兄弟 我帮你推
Come on, then, pal, I'll help you shift it.
你越早上路 就会越开心
Quicker you're on your way, the happier you'll be.
走起
There we go.
你需要帮忙吗
Do you want a hand?
不用 我们可以 亲爱的
No, we're all right, love.
别嘴硬 我比我看上去有力气
Well, you're not. I'm tougher than I look, honest.
这种事常发生吗  - 谢谢 兄弟
Does this happen a lot? - Cheers, mate.
我已经推了一周了
Been doing it all week.
自从那些孩子开始失踪 就这样了吗
Since those children started going missing?
对 差不多吧
Yeah. Suppose so.
痒痒
Hmm, tickles.
你玩什么把戏
What's your game?
我 蛇梯棋
My, um... Snakes And Ladders?
壁球也不错 相当不错
Quite good at squash... Reasonable.
我又乱开玩笑了吧
I'm being facetious, aren't I?
没必要
There's no call for it.
所有车都熄火 市政快疯了
Every car cuts out. Council are going nuts.
他们费了好些力气 改路名
They've given this street the works - renamed it.
我填平所有坑洼路面
I've been Tarmacking every pothole.
看看 漂亮吧
Look at that. Beauty, innit?
就因为奥林匹克火炬
Yep, and this is all because that Olympic torch
会在最后经过这里 就在那边
comes right by the end of this close. Just down there.
一切都要完美 对吧
Everything's gotta be perfect, ain't it?
可惜就是不完美
Only it ain't.
他们玩耍的时候被劫走了
It takes 'em when they're playing.
被什么带走  - 丹尼 简 戴尔
What takes them? - Danny, Jane, Dale...
一眨眼就没了
snatched in the blink of an eye.
我没说谎 我是警察
No, I'm not a liar, I'm a police officer.
我真的是 我有警徽和警车
That's what I am. I've got a badge and a police car.
我可以证明给你看
Know what I have to get. I can prove it.
我们在这附近见够警察了
We've had coppers poking around here
你看起来听起来一点也不像他们
and you don't look or sound like any of 'em.
看 这是我同事
See? Look! I've got a colleague!
她叫露易丝  - 她比你更不像警察
Lewis! - She looks less like a copper than you do!
见习新人 发型不对
Training, new recruit. Not that all hair-dressing, so...
看
Voila!
你准备怎么办
What are you going to do?
警察已经挨家挨户问过了
The police have knocked on every door
没线索 什么都没有
no clues, no leads, nothing!
孩子们有时候是会离家出走
Kids run off sometimes, all right?
他们就是会  - 我亲眼看见的
That's what they do. - I saw it with my own eyes.
戴尔·希克斯在你院子里玩
Dale Hicks in your garden playing
和汤姆一起 然后就
with your Tommy and then...
在我面前噗地一下
right in front of me.
像他从没去过那里一样
Like he was never there.
根本不用跑出这条街找
There's no need to look any further than this street.
凶手就在我们当中
It's right here amongst us!
我们不如  - 为什么不从他开始
Why don't we...? - Why don't we start with him?
这街上来了好些个人 没日没夜
There's been all sorts in this street, day and night.
我们是为了奥运会修路
Fixing things up for the Olympics!
可你真够磨蹭的
And taking a long time about it!
我认为 我们应该...
I'm of the opinion, that all we gonna do...
你刚说的是诽谤  - 我才不管
Look the word you just said. That's slander! - I don't care what it is!
我觉得我们  - 我要她道歉
I think we need to just... - I want an apology of her!
别找他的茬  - 对 别找我的茬
Stop picking on him! - Yeah, stop picking on me!
别装作没看见
And stop pretending to be blind!
这是魔鬼  - 我才不信鬼
It's evil! - I don't believe in evil.
你信的是铺路工人
You believe in Tarmackers with
车里都藏着绑架来的小孩
stuck loads of kidnapped kiddies in their van!
她不是这个意思  - 你们别抱团好吗
That's not what she's saying! - Stop ganging up on me?
心虚了 是吧
Feeling guilty, are we?
手都放嘴唇上
Fingers on Lips!
过去的六天
In the last six days,
你们这里有三个孩子被偷走了
three of your children have been stolen.
凭空消失了 对吗
Snatched out of thin air, right?
我能不能
Er, can I...?
看看周围
Look around you.
直到这事之前 这条街还很安全
This was a safe street till it came.
这不是一个人
It's not a person.
他们不愿意说 那我来说
I'll say it if no-one else will.
你或许是警察也或许不是
Maybe you're coppers and maybe you're not.
我不管你是什么 能不能帮帮我们
I don't care who you are, can you please help us?
你要手帕吗
You want a hanky?
你没闻到吗
Can you smell it?
你觉得这味道像什么
What's it remind you of?
某种 金属
Sort of...metal?
丹尼·爱德华兹骑着自行车进来
Danny Edwards cycled in one end
却没从另一头出现
but never came out the other.
又来了
Whoa, there it goes again.
快看我雄壮多毛的手背上的汗毛
Look at the hairs on the back of my manly hairy hand.
还有那味道
And there's that smell.
就好像
It's like a...
烧断的保险丝之类的
A burnt fuse plug or something.
还有残余能量
There's a residual energy in the spots
留在孩子们消失的地方
where the kids vanished.
不论是何物 这么做都消耗了不少能量
Whatever it was, it used an awful lot of power to do this.
你总要下楼的 克洛伊
You have to come down some time, Chloe...
我很忙 妈妈
I'm busy, Mum.
看看这里 你一定消耗了不少雨林
Look at it in here. You must've used up half a rainforest.
这是戴尔
That's Dale.
为什么你画的他这么悲伤
Why did you draw him so sad?
不是我画的他悲伤
I didn't draw him like that.
戴尔让自己难过的
Dale made himself sad.
所以我要给他画一个朋友
So I'm going to draw him a friend.
这是他需要的 更多朋友
That's what he needs - more friends.
你看电视了吗
Have you seen the TV?
直播 奥运会倒计时
看 这会让你高兴点 火炬要来了
Look, this'll cheer you up. The torch is getting close.
会从我们的街上经过
It'll pass right by our street.
今晚 他们会在体育场点燃奥运圣火
Tonight they'll light the Olympic flame in the stadium
全世界都会关注这个城市
and the whole world will be looking at our city.
你是不是觉得自己在经历着什么
I mean, doesn't that make you feel part of something? ..
亲爱的
Sweetheart?
克洛伊  - 我正忙呢 妈妈
Chloe? - I'm busy, Mum.
好吧
Ok.
你累了 克洛伊
You're tired, Chloe.
我昨晚又听到你尖叫了
I heard you calling out again last night.
我没事  - 做噩梦了吗
It's fine. - Nightmares?
我在画画
I'm drawing!
不论你梦到什么
Whatever they are...
那都只是梦 你知道吗
they're just dreams, you do know that?
他们没法伤害你
They can't hurt you.
我很忙 除非你想让我画你 妈妈
I'm busy! Unless you want me to draw you...Mum.
你想宅在这 那么好吧
If you want to stay cooped up in here, fine.
随便你
I'll leave you to it.
你是不是个漂亮的小朋友
Well, aren't you a beautiful boy!
谢谢 我试着留背头了
Thanks. I'm experimenting with back-combing.
我养过一只和你一样的
I used to have one like you.
怎么了
What?
我不喜欢猫
I'm not really a cat person.
当你被修女猫威胁以后
Once you've been threatened by one in a nun's wimple,
就再也感受不到其中的快乐了
it kind of takes the joy out of it.
过来 小猫咪
Come here, puss.
你干嘛去那里面
What d'you want to go in there for?
博士
Doctor!
离子残留 天哪 这需要些技巧
Ion residue. Blimey! That takes some doing.
从空间时间中取走一个活物
Just to snatch a living organism out of space-time.
就好像小孩说"我要这个" 令人赞叹
This baby's like, "I'm having some of that!" I'm impressed.
猫被传送了
So the cat's been transported.
它可以储存相当多的离子能量
It can harness huge reserves of ionic power.
我们需要找到能量来源
We need to find the source of that power.
找到来源你就能找到
Find the source and you will find...
偷走小孩和毛茸茸小动物的那东西
whatever has taken to stealing children and fluffy animals.
看看你能看到什么 盯紧点 露易丝
See what you can see. Keep 'em peeled, Lewis.
我给你找了朋友 你却还在难过
I've given you friends and you still moan.
难过 难过 难过 你们很幸运
Moan, moan, moan. You're lucky.
你们都在一起 你们不知道一个人的滋味
You're all together. You don't know what it is to be alone.
如果你们知道 你们会感谢我
If you did, you'd be thanking me.
不
No!
是你吗 小猫咪 你被困住了吗
Is that you, puss cat? You trapped?
不要打开 不要打开 不要打开
Not gonna open it, not gonna open it, not gonna open it...
呆着别动
Stay still!
还好吧
Okey-dokey?
还好 谢谢
Yeah. Cheers.
没事
No probs.
我想给你五块钱
I'll give you a fiver if you can tell me
只要你说出这是什么 我一点也想不出来
what the hell it is cos I haven't got the foggiest.
我能说你刚才杀了它
Well, I can tell you you've just killed it.
它本来就不是活的
It was never living.
它靠能量活动
It's animated by energy.
和抓人时的能量一样 这么不起眼
The same energy that's snatching people. So dinky!
可以到处走的东西
The go-anywhere creature.
能塞进口袋 交朋友
Fits in the pocket. Makes friends.
打动你老板 聚会时缓解尴尬气氛
Impresses your boss. Breaks the ice at parties.
好了
Hi, ho, here we go.
我们看看
Let's have a look.
不会吧  - 上面说什么
Get out of here! - What's it say?
还真是
It is!
这是石墨
It's graphite!
基本就是和HB铅笔同样的东西
Basically the same material as an HB pencil.
我被一团铅笔线攻击了
I was attacked by a pencil scribble?!
铅笔线生物
A scribble creature,
从离子能量中获得生命
brought into being with ionic energy.
我们正在对付的东西
Whatever we're dealing with,
可以创造生物 也能夺走生物
it can create things as well as take them.
但为什么要做个线团生物
But why make a scribble creature?
可能出错了
Maybe it was a mistake.
我的意思是 你涂一团线
I mean, you scribble over something
在想要涂掉的东西上 像画一样
when you want to get rid of it, like a drawing.
像
Like a...
小朋友的画
child's...drawing.
你说过它就在街上  - 大概吧
You said it was in the street. - Probably.
那个女孩  - 对啊 什么女孩
The girl. - Of course! ..What girl?
她身上有某种东西让我害怕
Something about her gave me the creeps.
哪怕她妈妈也怕她
Even her own mum looked scared of her.
你在推理吗
Are you deducting?
我想是的  - 警察的直觉
I think I am. - Copper's hunch?
请求追查 警官
Permission to follow it up, Sarge?
你好 我是博士 这是罗丝
Hello, I'm the Doctor and this is Rose.
我们可以见见你女儿吗
Can we see your daughter?
不行
No! You can't.
好吧 再见
OK. Bye.
为什么
Why?
你们为什么要见克洛伊
Why do you want to see Chloe?
这条街上发生了很有趣的事情
Well, there's some interesting stuff going on in this street
于是我想
and I just thought... Well,
我们想她可能能够帮我们
we thought that she might like to give us a hand.
不好意思打扰了  - 对 不好意思
Sorry to bother you. - Yeah, sorry.
你还是继续忙吧
We'll let you get on with things.
你一个人忙吧 再见
On your own. Bye again.
等等
Wait...
你能帮她吗
Can you help her?
当然可以
Yes, I can.
火炬接力者正在往商场跑去
'The torch-bearer is running up towards the Mall...'
她大部分时间呆在房间里
She stays in her room most of the time.
我试过和她说话
I try talking to her,
但就好像对着个墙壁说话似的
but it's like trying to speak to a brick wall.
她没有回应 只说要一个人呆着
She gives me nothing, just asks to be left alone.
克洛伊的父亲呢
What about Chloe's dad?
克洛伊的父亲一年前死了
Chloe's dad died a year ago.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你要是认识他就不会这么说了
You wouldn't be if you'd known him.
我们去问个好吧
Well, let's go and say hi.
我先去看看 她可能睡着了
I should check on her first, she might be asleep.
你为什么怕她 翠西
Why are you afraid of her, Trish?
在你见她之前 我想先告诉你
I want you to know, before you see her,
她真的是一个很棒的孩子
that she's really a great kid.
我相信她一定是
I'm sure she is.
她在学校从不惹麻烦
She's never been in trouble at school.
你应该看看她去年的报告
You should see her report from last year.
都是优和良
As and Bs.
我能用一下洗手间吗
Can I use your loo?
她参加了合唱团
She's in the choir.
她还在敬老院唱歌
She sings in old folks' homes.
任何一位母亲都会为她骄傲 你懂吗
Any mum would be proud, you know?
在你见她之前 我想先告诉你这些 博士
I want you to know these things before you see her, Doctor,
因为现在 她不是她自己
because right now, she's not herself.
你好啊
All right there?
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
我是克洛伊·韦伯
I'm Chloe Webber.
你好吗 克洛伊·韦伯
How are you doing, Chloe Webber?
我很忙 我在做事
I'm busy. I'm making something.
是不是 妈妈
Aren't I, Mum?
我说过 她很久没睡了
And like I said, she's not been sleeping.
可是你在画画呀
But you've been drawing, though.
我画得很烂
I'm rubbish.
火柴人就是我的极限了
Stick men are about my limit.
不过我能这样
Can do this though.
你行吗
Can you do that?
他们哭个不停  - 克洛伊
They don't stop moaning. - Chloe?
我试过帮他们 但他们还是一直哭
I try to help them but they don't stop moaning!
谁在哭  - 我们可以在一起
Who don't? - We can be together.
亲爱的  - 别碰我 妈妈
Sweetheart... - Don't touch me, Mum!
我来了
I'm coming!
我很忙 博士
I'm busy... Doctor.
克洛伊 别扫兴啊
Come on, Chloe, don't be a spoil-sport.
你在忙什么大事呢
What's the big project?
我可想知道了
I'm dying to know.
你在上面做什么呢
What are you making up there?
博士
Doctor!
我要来伤害你
I'm coming to hurt you!
看这个
Look at it!
不行谢谢
No, ta.
那是什么
What the hell was that?
一张画 人的脸  - 什么脸
A drawing - face of a man. - What face?
最好别  - 你画了些什么
Best not. - What have you been drawing?
我昨天画的他  - 谁
I drew him yesterday. - Who?
爸爸  - 你爸爸
Dad. - Your dad?
但他已经走很久了
But he's long gone.
克洛伊 这个世界那么美好 为什么画他
Chloe, with all the lovely things in the world, why him?
我梦到他 盯着我
I dream about him...staring at me.
我以为我们已经忘掉他了
I thought we were putting him behind us.
你到底是怎么回事
What's the matter with you?
我们要在一起  - 对
We need to stay together. - Yes, we do.
不 不是你 我们
No, not you, us.
我们要在一起 一切都会好的
We need to stay together and then it will be all right.
翠西 那些画
Trish...the drawings.
你看过克洛伊的画能做什么么
Have you seen what Chloe's drawings can do?
谁允许你进她房间的
Who gave you permission to come into her room?
出去
Get out of my house!
跟我们说说这些画 克洛伊
Tell us about the drawings, Chloe.
我不想再听下去了
I don't wanna hear any more of this.
但她爸爸的画像
But that drawing of her dad...
我听到了 他会说话
I heard a voice, he spoke!
他死了 这些都是小孩的画 出去
He's dead! And these? They're kids' pictures! Now get out!
克洛伊有能力 我不知道是怎么回事
Chloe has a power and I don't know how,
但她带走了丹尼·爱德华兹 戴尔·希克斯
but she's used it to take Danny Edwards, Dale Hicks.
她用能力夺走小孩  - 出去
She's using it to snatch the kids! - Get out!
你没看到画会动吗
Have you seen those drawings move?
不 我什么都没看到  - 不 你见过
No! I haven't seen anything. - Yes, you have.
你眼角瞥见过  - 不
Out of the corner of your eye. - No.
你无视掉了 因为不然你还能怎样
And you dismissed it because what choice you have.
你见到了无法解释的东西
You've seen something you can't possibly explain it.
你忽略掉 任何人一提你就会生气
You dismiss it rite? And if anyone mentions it, you get angry,
所以再也没有人敢说  - 她是个孩子
so it's never spoken of ever again. - She's a child.
然而你害怕她
And you're terrified of her.
但找不到人倾诉 因为谁会相信
But no one to turn to because who's going to believe
你眼角看到的东西呢 没人
the things you see in the corner of your eye? No-one.
除了我
Except me.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是来帮你的
I'm help.
那些画 它们是活的
Those pictures, they're alive.
她画人 人就进了画里
She draws people and they end up in her pictures.
离子能量
Ionic energy.
克洛伊收集这种能量 然后偷走孩子们
Chloe's harnessing it to steal those kids
放到离子能量笔里
in placement some kind of holding pen made up of ionic power.
那衣柜里的地狱爸爸怎么说
And what about the dad from hell in her wardrobe?
我要说多少次 他死了
How many times do I have to told you, he's dead.
就一个死人来说他的声音可够大的
Well, he's got a very loud voice for a dead bloke.
如果活物能变成画
If living things can become drawings
那么画或许也能变成活的
then maybe drawings can become living things.
克洛伊现实的爸爸已经死了
Chloe's real dad is dead.
可那个噩梦里造访她的爸爸还没有
But not the one who visits her in her nightmares.
那个爸爸非常真实
That dad seems very real,
既然已经被画出来了
and since that she's drawn him,
他离闯进这个世界只有一步之遥
he's a heartbeat away from crashing into this world.
他在世的时候对她非常不好
She always got the worst of it when he was alive.
博士 一个12岁女孩怎么会做到这一切
Doctor, how can a 12-year-old girl be doing any of this?
我们去问问吧
Let's find out.
不错
Nice one.
好了
There we go.
他不能  - 没问题 相信他
I can't let him... - it's OK. Trust him.
我们现在可以谈谈了
Now we can talk.
我要克洛伊
I want Chloe!
别管她
Leave her alone.
我要克洛伊
I want Chloe.
你是谁
Who are you?
我要克洛伊·韦伯
I want Chloe Webber.
你对我的小姑娘做了什么
What have you done to my little girl?
博士 这是什么
Doctor, what is it?
我在跟你说话
I'm speaking to you,
利用这个人类孩童的实体
the entity that is using this human child.
我要求依照《影子宣言》谈判
I request parlez in compliance with The Shadow Proclamation.
我才不在乎什么影子什么谈判
I don't care about shadows or policies.
那你在乎什么
So what do you care about?
我想交朋友
I wanna make friends.
你很孤独 我知道
You're lonely, I know.
说出你的身份
Identify yourself.
我是众多之一
I am one of many.
我与兄弟姐妹一起旅行
I travel with my brothers and sisters.
我们的旅行没有尽头
We take an endless journey.
是你寿命的几千倍
A thousand of your lifetimes.
但现在只有我一人
But now I am alone.
我讨厌这样
I hate it.
这不公平 我讨厌这样
It's not fair. I hate it.
报上姓名
Name yourself.
艾索洛斯
Isolus.
你是艾索洛斯 难怪
You're Isolus, of course!
我们旅行从深域开始
Our journey began in the Deep Realms
我们曾是一家
when we were a family.
那是什么
What's that?
艾索洛斯的母亲 在深空漂浮
The Isolus mother, drifting in deep space.
你看 她抛下成千上万孢子
See, she jettisons millions of fledgling spores
就是她的孩子
her children.
艾索洛斯是一种感情充沛的生物
The Isolus are empathic beings of intense emotion.
当他们离开母亲后
When they're cast off from their mother,
他们的情感联结
their empathic link,
他们互相之间的需要让他们活下去
their need for each other, is what sustains them.
他们需要在一起 不能分开
They need to be together. They cannot be alone.
我们的旅行太长
Our journey is long.
艾索洛斯的孩子们在荚内
The Isolus children travel, each inside a pod.
靠着太阳潮汐的热量和能量漂游
They ride the heat and energy of solar tides.
他们需要成千上万年
And it takes thousands
才能长大成年
and thousands of years for them to grow up.
成千上万年在太空漂游
Thousands of years just floating through space?
真可怜 他们不会无聊到疯吗
Poor things. Don't they go mad with boredom?
我们会游戏
We play.
你们 玩游戏
You...play?
他们旅行时 他们会玩游戏
While they travel, they play games.
他们用离子能量
They use their ionic power to
去创造虚构世界 在里面游戏
literally create make-believe worlds in which to play.
机上娱乐系统
In-flight entertainment.
可以让他们愉悦
It helps keep them happy.
他们愉悦时 就能从对方的爱意中汲取养料
While they're happy they can feed off each other's love.
没了爱 他们会迷失自己
Without it, they're lost.
那你为什么来地球
Why did you come to Earth?
我们太近了
We were too close!
这是你们的太阳的耀斑
That's a solar flare from your sun.
产生了太阳潮
Would have made a tidal wave
让艾索洛斯的荚分散了
of solar energy that scattered the Isolus pods.
只有我落到了地球
Only I fell to Earth.
我的兄弟姐妹还在上面
My brothers and sisters are left up there
我却触碰不到他们
and I can not reach them.
多么孤独
So alone!
你的荚坠落了 它在哪里
Your pod crashed? Where is it?
我的荚被热量吸引
My pod was drawn to heat
我被克洛伊·韦伯吸引
and I was drawn to Chloe Webber.
她就像我一样 孤独
She was like me - alone.
她需要我 我需要她
She needed me and I her.
你与她有共鸣
You empathized with her.
你想和她在一起
You wanted to be with her
因为她和你一样孤独
because she was alone like you.
我想要我的家人
I want my family!
这不公平
It's not fair!
我明白 你想要一个家
I understand, you want to make a family.
但你不能呆在这个孩子体内 这是不对的
But you can't stay in this child, it's wrong.
你不能为了自己再偷朋友了
You can't steal any more friends for yourself.
我很孤独
I am alone!
克洛伊 我来伤害你
Chloe, I'm coming to hurt you.
我来了
I'm coming!
翠西 你怎么安抚她  - 什么
Trish! How do you calm her? - What?!
她做噩梦时 你怎么做
When she has nightmares, what do you do?
我
I...
你做什么  - 我唱歌
What do you DO? - I sing to.
现在开始唱
Start singing.
克洛伊 我来了
Chloe, I'm coming.
笑翠鸟坐在老桉树上
Kookaburra sits in the old gum tree.
克洛伊
Chloe!
笑翠鸟你的生活一定好愉快
Kookaburra Gay your life must be.
它找上她因为她很孤独
It came to her because she was lonely.
克洛伊 对不起
Oh, Chloe, I'm sorry.
他发脾气时总是冲着克洛伊
Chloe usually got the brunt of his temper,
他喝酒以后就会这样
when he'd had a drink.
他撞车那天我还以为我们解脱了
The day he crashed the car, I thought we were free.
我以为都结束了
I thought it was over.
你和她谈过吗
Did you talk to her about it?
我不想谈
I didn't want to.
但也许这就是克洛伊孤独的原因
But maybe that's why Chloe feels so alone.
因为她有那些关于爸爸的噩梦
Because she has these terrible dreams about her dad
她却不能跟你说
but she can't talk to you about them.
她和艾索洛斯
Her and the Isolus  -
两个孤单的孩子需要对方
two lonely kids who needed each other.
它也不会放手 是不是 博士
It won't stop, will it, Doctor?
它会不断地拽孩子进去
It'll just keep pulling kids in.
它渴望被爱
It's desperate to be loved.
它习惯于拥有一个大家庭
It's used to a pretty big family.
多大
How big?
大概有40亿
Say around four billion?
人们一周前就开始排队
The queue started a week ago
都渴望着能进场
for those desperate enough to be inside  -
人数非常多
there are lots of them.
我们预计现场会有8万人
We're expecting a capacity crowd of 80,000
观看这次开幕式
for this evening's opening ceremony.
我必须说
I have to say there's been...'
我们需要找到荚
We need that pod.
它坠毁了 难道不会已经毁坏了吗
It crashed. Won't it be destroyed?
它吸收了那么多热能
Well, it's been sucking in all the heat it can.
应该能使它保持状态准备发射
That should keep it fit to launch.
应该就在不远
It must be close.
它会留下微弱的能量信号让塔迪斯跟踪到
It should have a weak energy signature the Tardis can trace.
我们找到荚 就能阻止艾索洛斯
Once we find it, then we can stop the Isolus.
她发烧了
She's running a temperature.
我现在没办法详说 克里斯蒂
..I can't go into that now, Kirsty.
对 我们找了医生
Yes, we've got a doctor.
对 他说他能帮她
..Yes, he said he can help her.
我们可以扫描与铅笔线生物
We can scan for the same trace I picked up
相同的信号
from the scribble creature.
只需要稍微扩大扫描范围
Just need to widen the field a bit.
艾索洛斯还没开口你就知道它很孤独了
You knew the Isolus was lonely before it told you.
你怎么知道的
How?
我懂一个人长期旅行的感觉
I know what it's like to travel a long way on your own.
给我石磁
Give me the steino-magnetic...
你左手边的那个
the thing in your left hand.
听上去你站在它那边
Sounds like you're on its side.
我同情它 仅此而已
I sympathize, that's all.
艾索洛斯给这些人带来了很多痛苦
The Isolus has caused a lot of pain for these people.
它只是个孩子
It's a child.
所以它才找上了克洛伊 两个孤独的小孩
That's why it went to Chloe. Two lonely mixed-up kids.
在我看来它像发脾气了
Feels to me like a temper tantrum
只因为得不到想要的东西
cos it can't get its own way.
它吓坏了
It's scared. Come on,
你也曾经是孩子 给我双体点
you were a kid once. Binary dot.
对 我也知道小孩是什么样
Yes, and I know what kids can be like.
小恶魔
Right little...terrors.
口香糖  - 我有堂表亲
Gum. - Hey, I've got cousins.
孩子们的要求不可能全满足
Kids can't have it all their own way.
这就是家庭的一部分
That's part of being a family.
那试着理解他们怎么样
And what about trying to understand them?
你说的轻松 你又没有小孩
Easy for you to say, you don't have kids.
我以前当过父亲
I was a dad... once.
你说什么
What did you say?
我觉得我们做好了
I think we're there.
恐惧和孤独是两大原因 罗丝
Fear. Loneliness. They're the big ones, Rose.
一些可怕的行为根源就是它们
Some terrible acts have been inspired by them.
但同时我们面对的不是想征服或毁灭的东西
But then we are not dealing with something that wants to conquer or destroy.
想要在这个宇宙通行无阻 你需要很多东西
There's a lot of things you need to get across this universe,
曲速引擎 虫洞折射镜
warp drive, wormhole refractors.
你知道你最需要什么吗
Do you know the thing you need most of all?
你需要一只可以牵起的手
You need a hand to hold.
不 我只是在指这个
No, look, I'm pointing.
是荚 它真的在这条街
It's the pod! It IS in the street!
一切都开始慢慢浮现 博士
Everything's coming up Doctor!
大概60厘米宽
It's about two inches across.
灰色 像海鸥蛋 很轻
Dull grey, like a gull's egg. Very light.
这些荚利用热能在太阳中穿行 对吗
So these pods, they travel from sun to sun, using the heat, yeah?
不全是靠着爱
So it's not all about love and stuff.
荚难道不是只需要热能吗
Doesn't the pod just need heat?
博士
Doctor?
Doctor!
没事的 我已经拿走她所有的铅笔了
It's OK, I've taken all the pencils off her.
别管我 我想和克洛伊·韦伯在一起
Leave me alone! I want to be with Chloe Webber!
我爱克洛伊·韦伯
I love Chloe Webber.
放他回来  - 不
Bring him back now. - No!
你知道你在做什么吗
Don't you realise what you've done?
他是唯一可以帮你的人
He was the only one who could help you.
现在放他回来  - 别管我
Now bring him back! - Leave me alone!
我爱克洛伊·韦伯
I love Chloe Webber!
我知道
I know.
博士 如果你听得见
Doctor, if you can hear me,
我会把你救出来
I'm going to get you out of there.
我会找到荚
I'll find the pod.
不要让她一个人呆着 不管发生什么
Don't leave her alone, no matter what.
火炬手离奥林匹克体育场越来越近了
The torchbearer is getting closer to the Olympic Stadium,
沿着斯特兰德大街
heading down The Strand
直到在
'before turning east...'
热能
Heat.
它们靠热能穿行
They travel on heat.
看看这成果 像婴儿屁股一样圆滑
Look at this finish. Smooth as a baby's bottom.
不凹也不凸
Not a bump or a lump.
凯尔 这条街上前几天
Kel, was there anything in this street
有没有什么东西产生巨大热能
the last few days giving off a lot of heat?
我是说 你可以在上面吃晚饭
I mean, you could eat your dinner off this.
太美了
Beautiful.
所以你说说为什么所有车都在这里趴窝
So you tell me why the other one's got a lump in it
这个坑我明明和其他几个填得一模一样
when I gave it the same craftsmanship as I did this one?
当你想出原因
Well, when you've worked it out
你可以写一本关于铺路的大书
put it in a big book about Tarmacking.
不过这之前 想想过去的六天
But before you do that, think back six days.
六天前
Six days?
我第一次铺这一块的时候  - 什么
When I was laying this the first time round? - What?
那是我第一次填这个坑
That's when I filled in this pothole for the first time.
六天前  - 对
Six days ago. - Yeah.
热 新鲜沥青
Hot, fresh tar.
按照市政的秘密配方混合
Blended to a secret council recipe.
我可没把配方藏在车里
And I don't keep it in the van.
这是市政车 快出来
Hey! That's a council van! Out!
等等
Whoa! Wait a minute!
你刚从市政车里拿走了一把市政铁镐
You've just removed a council axe from a council van.
放回去 别别 这是我的车
Put it back. No, don't. That's my van.
给我铁镐 等等 住手
Give me the axe. Wait! No! No! You stop!
你从市政车里面拿走了市政铁镐
You just took a council axe from a council van
现在你在挖市政路
and now you're digging up a council road!
我要找政府举报你
I'm reporting you to the council!
它选择了这条街上最热的东西
It went for the hottest thing in the street
你的沥青
your tar!
这是什么  - 这是一艘太空飞船
What is it? - It's a spaceship!
恐怕不是市政飞船
Not a council spaceship, I'm afraid.
这里是BBC新闻24小时直播
We are live on BBC News 24.
2012伦敦奥运会开幕式即将开始
The opening ceremony of the London Olympics of 2012 is well under way.
全世界的运动员们正进入体育场
Athletes all over world are streaming into the stadium right now.
他们都带着各自的梦想
They all have their dreams.
他们多年的努力
They've all put in years of hard work...'
我找到了
I found it!
我不知道该拿它怎么办
Don't know what to do with it
但艾索洛斯或许能跳上船
but maybe the Isolus will just hop on board.
等等 我说过别离开她
Hang on, I told you not to leave her.
天哪
My God!
这里怎么回事
What is going on here?
我才不管你把白雪公主和七个小矮人埋里面了
I don't care if Snow White and the Seven Dwarves buried under there,
你不能  - 闭嘴 看
you do not... - Shut up and look!
观众消失了
The crowd has vanished.
他们没了 所有人都消失了
Em, they are gone. Everyone has gone.
成千上万人消失了
Thousands of people have just gone, er,
在我眼前消失了 太不可思议了
'er, right in front of my eyes. It's impossible.
鲍勃 你那边怎么样
'Bob, can we join you in the box?
鲍勃
Bob?!
鲍勃你也不见了
Not you too, Bob?'
一个体育场不够
A stadium won't be enough.
艾索洛斯有40亿兄弟姐妹
The Isolus has four billion brothers and sisters.
超过8万名观众和1万3千名的运动员
Over 80,000 spectators and 13,000 athletes...'
不够  - 消失了
Not enough. - ..They're gone.
所有人全都消失了
All of those people.
真是一个可怕的变故
It's a terrible, terrible turn of events...'
我们不会孤单 克洛伊·韦伯
We won't be alone, Chloe Webber.
我们将拥有他们所有人
We'll have all of them.
他们永远都不再会孤单了
And they all won't feel alone ever again.
克洛伊  - 克洛伊 我是罗丝 开门
Chloe? - Chloe? It's Rose. Open the door!
我们找到你的飞船了 我们可以送你回家
We found your ship! We can send you home.
克洛伊  - 开门
Chloe! - Open up!
后退
Right, stand back.
我要出来伤害你
I'm coming to hurt you.
我来了 我来伤害你 克洛伊
I'm coming. Coming to hurt you, Chloe!
克洛伊  - 我来伤害你
Chloe! - I'm coming to hurt you.
我来了  - 我必须阻止她
I'm coming... - I have to stop her.
你如果阻止克洛伊·韦伯 我就放他出来
If you stop Chloe Webber, I will let him out.
我们一起放他出来
We will let him out together!
我不能孤单一人
I cannot be alone!
这不公平
It's not fair!
我找到你的飞船
I've got your pod!
荚已经死了  - 不不 它只是需要热能
The pod is dead! - No, no. It only needs heat.
它不止需要热能  - 那还需要什么
It needs more than heat. - What, then?
我不是想开玩笑
I'm not being funny or nothing...
那张画真的动了
but that picture just moved.
还有那个
And that one!
这不是她画的 是他画的
She didn't draw that, he did.
它不仅仅需要热能 博士
But it needs more than heat, Doctor!
仍在路上 我想现在这已经不只是一支火炬
'..Is still on its way. I suppose it's more than a torch now.
它成了一个灯塔
'It's a beacon.
是希望 坚毅与勇气的灯塔
It's a beacon of hope and fortitude and courage.
是爱的灯塔
And it's a beacon of love.'
爱
Love!
我们从直升机上望去
So let's have a look from the helicopter.
这是火炬手
There we go the torchbearer...'
我知道怎么给荚充电了
I know how to charge up the pod!
经过凯利福尔摩斯女爵巷
..Past Dame Kelly Holmes Close...
对不起 你只能从这里看
Sorry, you'll have to watch from here.
我必须更近一点  - 不行
Yeah. I've got to get closer! - No way.
我可以阻止这一切发生
I can stop this happening!
克洛伊 克洛伊 我来伤害你
Chloe... Chloe! I'm coming to hurt you.
我不准你再伤害她  - 克洛伊 我来了
You're not going to hurt her again! - Chloe! I'm coming!
你感觉到了 是不是
You felt it, didn't you?
感受这爱吧
Feel the love.
太好了
Yeah!
我可以回家了
I can go home.
再见 克洛伊·韦伯
Goodbye, Chloe Webber.
我爱你
I love you.
妈妈
Mum?
我在这
I'm here.
妈妈
Mummy!
做得好 你做到了
Nice one! You did it!
你刚才做什么了
What was it you did?
妈妈
Mummy.
简
Jane!
博士
Doctor?
我不知道你是谁也不知道你做了什么
I don't know who you are or what you did
不过谢谢你 亲爱的
but thank you, darling.
也帮我谢谢那个人
And thank that man for me too.
他在哪 他应该在这的
Where is he? He should be here?
所有画都活了
All the drawings have come to life.
这意味着所有的
That means all of them.
不
Oh, no.
出来  - 我做不到 门被卡住了
Get out! - I can't. The door's stuck.
博士在吗  - 不在
Is the Doctor in there? - I don't think so.
妈妈
Mummy!
克洛伊 我要来伤害你了
Chloe, I'm coming to hurt you!
求求你了 爸爸 别
Please, Dad...no more.
克洛伊  - 克洛伊 听我说
Chloe! - Chloe, listen to me.
它不像其他人都是真的
It isn't real like the others.
这只是艾索洛斯残余的能量
It's just energy left over by the Isolus.
你可以摆脱它的
You can get rid of it, Chloe!
帮帮我们
Help us!
因为你的恐惧它才变得这样真实
It's because you're so scared that he's real.
但你可以摆脱它的 克洛伊  - 妈妈
But you can get shot of him, Chloe. - Mummy!
你能做到 克洛伊  - 我做不到
You can do it, Chloe! - I can't!
克洛伊 我来了  - 我做不到
Chloe, I'm coming! - I can't!
我来了  - 我做不到
I'm coming... - I can't.
我来了  - 妈妈
I'm coming... - Mummy!
克洛伊
Chloe!
我和你在一起 克洛伊 你不是一个人
I'm with you, Chloe. You're not alone.
你再也不会孤单了
You'll never be alone again.
克洛伊 克洛伊 唱吧
Chloe! Chloe, sing!
笑翠鸟坐在  - 克洛伊 克洛伊
Kookaburra sits... - Chloe! Chloe!
克洛伊
Chloe!
克洛伊 我来伤害你
Chloe! I'm coming to hurt you.
笑呀 笑翠鸟 笑呀
Laugh kookaburra, laugh
笑翠鸟你的生活一定好愉快
kookaburra Gay your life must be.
笑呀 笑翠鸟 笑呀
Laugh kookaburra, laugh
笑翠鸟你的生活一定好愉快
Kookaburra Gay your life must be...
笑翠鸟坐在老桉树上
Kookaburra sits in the old gum tree
他是森林的欢乐欢乐国王
Merry, merry king of the bush is he
笑呀 笑翠鸟 笑呀
Laugh kookaburra, laugh
笑翠鸟你的生活一定好愉快
kookaburra Gay your life must be.
他也许去别的地方了
Maybe he's gone somewhere.
现在谁来牵起他的手
Who's gonna hold his hand now?
看看这个
Just look at this  -
奥林匹克体育场发生完全不可思议的一幕
utterly incredible scenes at the Olympic Stadium.
8万名运动员和观众
80,000 athletes and spectators,
他们消失了 又回来了
they disappeared, they've come back.
他们回来了 他们重新出现了 不可思议
They returned. They've re-appeared. It's quite incredible.
鲍勃 这一定是
Bob, this was certainly...'
8万人 博士在哪
80,000 people, so where's the Doctor?
我需要他
I need him!
等等 火炬手似乎遇到了些问题
Hang on! The torch-bearer seems to be in trouble.
早些时候我们看到一束闪电
We did see a flash of lightning earlier
似乎击中他了
that seemed to strike him.
或许他受伤了 他肯定有些麻烦了
'Maybe he's injured. He's definitely in trouble.
难道说奥林匹克精神死了吗
Does this mean that the Olympic dream is dead?'
博士
Doctor...
有个神秘人
There's a mystery man.
他拾起圣火 我们不知道他是谁
He's picked up the flame and we've no idea who he is.
他举着圣火 对
He's carrying the flame. Yes,
他举着圣火 没人想阻止他
he's carrying the flame and no-one wants to stop him.
这已经不仅仅是火焰了 鲍勃
It's more than a flame now, Bob.
这不仅仅是热与光
It's more than heat and light  -
这是希望 是勇气 是爱
it's hope and it's courage and it's love.
去吧 加入你的兄弟姐妹
Go on, join your brothers and sisters.
他们一定等了很久
They'll be waiting.
要蛋糕吗
Cake?
头等大事
Top banana!
我说多少遍都不嫌多 能吃的滚珠
I can't stress this enough - ball-bearings you can eat.
大师之作
Masterpiece!
我以为我失去你了
I thought I'd lost you.
不会的 不会在这样的晚上
Nah, not on a night like this.
今晚是失而复得的夜晚
This is a night for lost things being found.
来吧  - 现在去哪里
Come on. - What now?
我想去看奥运会 我们就是为了这个来的
I want to go to the Games, it's what we came for.
给点提示
Go on, give us a clue.
我们哪些项目表现不错
Which events do we do well in?
我这么说吧
I will tell you this,
巴布新几内亚在铅球项目给了所有人一个惊喜
Papua New Guinea surprise everyone in the shot-put.
真的 你开玩笑的吧
Really? You're joking, aren't you?
博士
Doctor?
你是认真的还是开玩笑  - 等着瞧
Are you serious or are you joking? - Wait and see.
你知道么 他们总是想分开我们
You know what? They keep on trying to split us up,
但他们永远不会得逞
but they never ever will.
永远别说永远
Never say "Never ever".
不会的 我们总是会顺利的 你和我
Nah, we'll always be OK, you and me.
你不觉得吗 博士
Don't you reckon, Doctor?
空气里有些东西 正在靠近  - 什么
Something in the air. Something coming. - What?
暴风雨要来了
A storm's approaching.
这是一个地球大战的故事
This is the story of war on Earth.
勇敢的孩子很快就会死在战争中
The valiant child who will die in battle so very soon.
它说我会死在战争中  - 那就是它说谎了
Said I was going to die in battle. - Then it lied.
下集预告
欢迎来到火炬木
Welcome to Torchwood!
我早上起来
I woke up one morning and
就在那了 到处都是鬼魂
there they all were, ghosts everywhere.
但如果我是敌人 我现在难道是战俘
But if I'm the enemy, does that mean I'm a prisoner?
当然
Oh yes.
你要把这个抬去哪里
Oi, where are you taking that?
外星的就是我们的
If it's alien, it's ours.
我们这里有个问题 依芙
We've got a problem down here. Yvonne,
你能听得到吗  - 我们把它送回地狱
can you hear me? - Send that thing back into hell!
博士
The Doctor,
在我们面前作威作福
lording it over us,
总是认为外星权威高于人类人权
assuming alien authority over the rights of man.
他们是裂缝中渗出的血液
They're bleeding through the fault lines,
从他们的世界穿过虚无来到你们的世界
walking from their world across the void and into yours.
你没法阻止我们 博士
You can't stop us, Doctor.
这个世界撞上了另外一个  - 就位
This world is colliding with another. - Positions!
它们是什么
Who are they?
赛博人
Cybermen!
那就是一切终结的时刻
That's when it all ended.
这是我讲述的最后一个故事
This is the last story I'll ever tell.
在2009年和2014年所做的两次官方民调中
本集都是新版最不受喜爱的一集
本集剧情启发了部分粉丝 他们发起请愿
要求DT参加2012伦敦奥运的火炬接力
不过最后是十一任博士MS在威尔士参加了火炬接力